## **loannis Linardos**

#### Contact details

Location: Enschede, The Netherlands Email: <a href="me@ioannislinardos.com">me@ioannislinardos.com</a>
Phone number: +31 617310845
Website: ioannislinardos.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ioannis-linardos

Visa status: EU national (sponsorship required in the UK)

### Personal Profile

I am a conscientious and action-oriented Data Scientist with qualifications in Computer Science and Applied Mathematics. I am looking for an entry-level position or paid internship as a data scientist, data analyst or machine learning practitioner. I have a passion for making sense of data and extracting the value hidden in them. I have approximately two years of experience in academic and industrial projects, specializing in machine learning, statistics, operations research and data management. I also followed courses in philosophy, psychology and management.

#### Education

#### 09.2019-11.2021: University of Twente, MSc, Applied Mathematics

- GPA: 8.3/10 (master thesis pending)
- Specialization in Mathematics of Data Science
- Relevant coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Statistics, Big Data,
   Network Science, Operations Research, Probabilistic Programming
- Completed Honours Programme: "Change Leaders Track" (a programme focused on personal development, leadership skills and change management)

### 09.2016-07.2019: University of Twente, BSc, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics (double degree)

- GPA: 8.1/10 (Cum Laude)
- Completed Honours Programme: "Philosophy Track"

#### 09.2012-06.2015: National Technical University of Athens, Greece, Mechanical Engineering (withdrew)

- GPA: 8.6/10
- Christos Papakyriakopoulos award (for top performance in mathematics)

## Work Experience

#### 09.2018-Present: University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands – Teaching Assistant

- Assisted in teaching:
  - o BSc level Mathematics (Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Statistics)
  - Python programming
- Participated in grading of projects and exams

#### 09.2020-12.2020: Sioux Technologies, Eindhoven, The Netherlands - Research Intern

- Implemented a deep learning framework for signal quality assessment on fetal heart rate data
- Framed the problem as anomaly detection using autoencoders and Generative Adversarial Networks
- Utilized TensorFlow/Keras, NumPy, SciPy and scikit-learn
- Contacted with external customers and incorporated their requirements
- Grade: 8.5/10

#### 02.2019-05.2019: Hospital Group Twente, Hengelo, The Netherlands – Student Trainee

- University-industry collaboration
- Built interactive web platform as an annotation tool to facilitate medical reporting using Java, JavaScript and SQL
- Integrated Natural Language Processing tool for automatic annotation
- Incorporated requirements of end-users

#### 06.2015-09.2015: Aluminum of Greece, Paralia Distomou, Greece - Engineering Intern

- Data entry and data wrangling/cleaning
- Used spreadsheet and office software (primarily MS Excel)

#### 09.2011-06.2012: Hellenic Army, Cyprus – Military Service

- Served in Special Operation Forces
- Promoted to non-commissioned officer (corporal)
- Led squad of 20 privates on daily chores

## Other Projects

# 03.2021-Present: Effects of Behaviour Adaptation on the Spread of Infectious Disease on Networks with Community Structures (Master Thesis)

- Simulating the spread of infectious disease (using digital twin technology)
- Research on the effects of network structure on disease spread using Graph Theory
- Stochastic modelling of the development of dynamic systems using differential equations

#### 11.2019-01.2020: Twitter Reaction on the Moscow Protests 2019

- Scrapped Twitter data (250 GB) related to the Moscow protests and conducted quantitative and sentiment analysis (Natural Language Processing)
- Examined the correlation between tweets and event attendance
- Big data wrangling and analysis using Apache Hadoop and Apache Spark

#### 11.2019-01.2020: Style Transfer via CycleGAN

- Used Generative Adversarial Networks to perform emoji style transfer
- Utilized PyTorch

#### 02.2019-06.2019: Multiscale Convolutions for Neural Networks (Bachelor Thesis)

- Built Convolutional Neural Networks for audio classification using TensorFlow/Keras
- Developed methods to scale the trained networks so that they can be used with higher and lower resolution recordings
- Grade: 8/10

## Computer Skills

- Experienced in: Python, SQL, Java, Linux systems
- Exposure in: R, Spark, Hadoop, MATLAB, JavaScript, C

## Languages

Greek (native) - English (fluent) - French (intermediate) - Dutch (beginner)

## Voluntary Work

## 05.2019-11.2020: T.S.V. Pro Deo (improvisation theatre association), Enschede, The Netherlands – Secretary

- Responsible for the flow and storage of information in the association
- Implemented change intervention by adapting improvisation theatre and social activities during the COVID-19 pandemic

#### 11.2018-01.2019: WINS Foundation, Bali, Indonesia – Volunteer Teacher

- Taught English, computer skills and mathematics to elementary and secondary school students
- Conducted field study on the motivations of volunteers